KARAN JAIN

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

+917987853691 | karanjain2212@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio|

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer who specializes in JavaScript, React, Redux, Node Js, and Ruby on Rails to build highly scalable websites. Demonstrated strength in remote collaboration, quick learning, adaptability and effective communication by having successfully worked with global teams on several diverse projects during 1.5 years of full time coding bootcamp -Microverse. Possesses over 3 years of experience as a systems engineer at Infosys. Expertise spans analyzing business requirements, software development, implementation, and user support.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, C#, HTML, CSS, ASP.NET (Web Forms and MVC),ADO.NET Back-End: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools, ServiceNow **Professional**: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, problem-solving, and critical thinking

EXPERIENCE

Highlighted Personal Projects

Remote

Full-stack web developer

Aug 2022 - Present

• Worked on over 40 projects both in teams and solo : HTML5/CSS3, JS, React/Redux, Ruby on Rails. Some of the projects are:

TheRecipieApp — A visually captivating, fast, and responsive website boasting an impressive collection of over **500 recipes** across various categories. Users can search for recipes based on specific ingredients.

- Built with: HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, ES6, Webpack, Web API's, Linters
- Github Live Demo

Shopping Spree - e-commerce website project, boasts cutting-edge **SAAS design** with an ultra-modern flair. Packed with interactive elements, including a shopping cart, category pages, and product descriptions.

- Built with: REACT, REDUX, REDUX toolkit, HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, API
- Github Live Demo

Space Traveler's Hub —A front-end web application that displays **SpaceX Rockets using their API**. Users can rent their favorite rockets and register for SpaceX missions.

- Built with: REACT, REDUX, REDUX toolkit, HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, API
- Github Live Demo

Weather App- Single Page Application (SPA) showcasing comprehensive weather data for **all countries**, **including their states and cities**. With **15+ weather metrics**, easily select a country to access detailed weather conditions for specific states and territories.

- Built with: REACT, REDUX, REDUX toolkit, HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, API
- Github Live Demo

BnB Homes - A full-stack app that allows users to signup, see a list of homes, and reserve or manage reservations and also list their own home .It uses a proper **authentication system**

• Built with: REACT, REDUX, REDUX toolkit, Tailwind-CSS, Ruby on Rails

• Github

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

Aug 2022 - Jun 2023

- Mentored 4 Junior Web Developers, cutting coding time by ~20% for heightened productivity.
- Delivered hands-on guidance and rigorous code reviews, fostering unprecedented progress.
- Achieved ~35% design excellence and ~25% system performance boost, setting new web
 development standards.
- Secured a perfect 100% satisfaction rating, with mentees excelling under my mentorship.

Infosys Ltd Bangalore, India

Sr Systems Engineer

June 2014 - July 2017

- Handled entire support of Air Miles Middle East and Nectar ITALY, which involved setting up customized loyalty programs and managing the points flow, ensuring 100% client satisfaction.
- Designed UI using asp.net 4.0, C# to call the jobs and SSIS packages for the creation of files and data warehousing processes which reduced the delivery time by 25% and error to 0%
- Resolved numerous client service and technical issues within the Service Now ticketing system in record time, collaborating closely with the Product Owner and BA for the implementation of CRs.

Aryan Textiles, Jabalpur, India

Jabalpur, India

Founder, Operations Manager

Jan 2018 - Dec 2022

- Orchestrated end-to-end production, ensuring quality, on-time delivery, and operational optimization.
 Increasing production 5x in 4 years
- Led a 20-member team, achieving production targets through adept team management and coordination.
- Transferring 4+ years of manufacturing expertise into web projects, ensuring efficient, data-driven, stakeholder-focused execution, consistently meeting quality, timeline, and budget objectives.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

Aug 2022 – Jun 2023

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate professionally and collaborate with international remote developers.

Infosys Global Education Center Mysore India

Jun 2014 - Dec 2014

Systems Engineer trainee

- Trained in OOPs Concepts, Oracle PL/SQL, C#, as major Programming languages.
- Trained in Microsoft Dot-Net technologies like ASP.net, ADO.net, MVC and WCF.
- Completed the stream with CGPA score of 5.0/5.0.

Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore India

Btech, Biomedical Engineering

Completed with a CGPA score of 8/10.

March 2010 - Apr 2014